<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Muhammed Uluyol</title>
    <link>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Muhammed Uluyol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:38:31 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LA Galbi (Korean Short Ribs)</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/la-galbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:38:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/la-galbi/</guid>
      <description>This dish is low effort and tastes great. You will need a food processor.
Originally, I tried a somewhat complex recipe (substituting maple syrup for mirin, since mirin contains alcohol) and it got me hooked. But I now prefer this simpler recipe from POV Husband since it requires less ingredients (both number and volume) while offering a very similar taste.
4 lbs of beef short ribs 1 whole korean pear (often called asian pear) 10 garlic cloves 1 tbsp fresh ginger &amp;frac12; onion &amp;frac12; cup brown sugar &amp;frac12; cup soy sauce 1 tbsp sesame oil &amp;frac12; tbsp black pepper (Optional) sesame seeds to garnish Directions Peel the pear and cut into chunks the food processor can handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Leg</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/lamb-leg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:38:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/lamb-leg/</guid>
      <description>My go-to recipe for making boneless leg of lamb, whether I spit roast it on a grill, or slow roast it in the oven. This recipe was taken from my wife, Bayan, with minor tweaks.
I usually eyeball how much of everything to put, but I recorded how much I used when I most recently grilled it. You may need to adjust these — especially salt — for baking.
5 &amp;frac12; lbs boneless leg of lamb 1 &amp;frac12; onions 6 cloves of garlic &amp;frac34; tbsp of salt 4 tsp black pepper 1 tsp cumin 2 tsp paprika 1 tbsp olive oil Rosemary Directions For baking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tandoori Chicken</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/tandoori-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 16:07:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/tandoori-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Marinading the Chicken 1 &amp;frac12; lbs chicken (thigh is better than breast) &amp;frac12; cup greek yogurt 1 &amp;frac12; tbsp oil (ideally mustard oil) 1 tbsp ginger garlic paste 1 tbsp lemon juice 1 tsp garam masala 1 tsp red chili powder (kashmiri or any other low-heat chili) 1 tsp coriander powder 1 tsp dried fenugreek leaves (if you can find them) &amp;frac14; tsp salt &amp;frac14; tsp black pepper &amp;frac14; tsp turmeric Add everything except the chicken to a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neapolitan Pizza</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/neapolitan-pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:30:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/neapolitan-pizza/</guid>
      <description>Makes 6 pizzas using a cast-iron skillet. Tastes really good but the recipe is quite involved — you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use both your oven&amp;rsquo;s broil setting and the cooktop.
Dough 4 cups flour 2 &amp;frac14; tsp salt 1 tsp instant yeast 2 tsp sugar 12 oz water Olive oil for working on the counter top (if you want, you can dust flour instead) Combine flour, salt, yeast, and sugar in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a dough hook attachment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basque Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/basque-cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:38:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/recipes/basque-cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>Easy and tasty dessert. Not too sweet and very light for a cheesecake.
1 &amp;frac12; lbs cream cheese 1 &amp;frac12; cups sugar 5 eggs &amp;frac12; cups heavy cream &amp;frac12; tsp salt 1 tsp vanilla extract Directions Let cold ingredients warm to room temperature, if possible. Pre-heat oven to 475°F convection with rack in the middle of the oven. Line a 7-inch cake pan with parchment paper, making sure that parchment fully covers all the sides of the pan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
