<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Muhammed Uluyol</title>
    <link>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Muhammed Uluyol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uluyol.xyz/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Tricks</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/cxx-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/cxx-tricks/</guid>
      <description>C++ is one hell of a programming language (for better or worse). This is a collection of C++ programming tricks that are useful, interesting, or just plain crazy:
 Detecting in C++ whether a type is defined (Raymond Chen)  Part 1: The initial plunge Part 2: Giving it a special name Part 3: SFINAE and incomplete types Part 4: Predeclaring things you want to probe Part 5: Augmenting the basic pattern    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Collection</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/collection/</guid>
      <description>Of Active Interest  Collection of articles from industry about things Tricks for mixed integer programming  The Rest Links to Some of my Projects  xkcd feed with captions  Compilers and Runtime Environments  WebAssembly for Edge Computing: @Cloudflare, @Fastly Mini-series on JVM internals, 2018 User-Level Thread Scheduling on Linux, 2013 Statically Recompiling NES Games into Native Executables, 2013 Fast Enough VMs in Fast Enough Time, 2012. How PyPy works and how you can use it to quickly build a JIT compiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles about Industry Experience</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/information-about-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/information-about-industry/</guid>
      <description>This page contains various articles about industry that could be useful from a research standpoint. I am collecting articles about things like hardware specs, application architectures, and failures that caused service downtime.
Hardware Specs  Cloudflare  2013 2018   Stack Exchange  2016    Application Design  Internet Native Applications - Cloudflare Dropbox erasure coding data acros data centers Hashicorp on why people want multi-cloud deployments Reddit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks for Mixed Integer Programming</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/tricks-for-mixed-integer-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/tricks-for-mixed-integer-programming/</guid>
      <description>This page contains various transformations I have found useful for producing MIP formulations. Many of these can be found spread on other websites as well. I will try to be consistent about notation: a, b, c, &amp;hellip; will to refer to binary variables while x, y, z, &amp;hellip; will refer to integer variables unless otherwise specified. Syntax follows the CPLEX LP file format.
Contents  Boolean Operations At Most One is True Product of Binary and (Bounded) Integer Variables (Bounded) Integer Comparison Result (Bounded) Integer Comparison Bound Rounded Up Division by Constant Rounded Down Division by Constant  Transformations Boolean Operations To make c = a AND b</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Meta Output</title>
      <link>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/device-meta-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uluyol.xyz/notes/device-meta-output/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>